

- New Zealand Citizen
- 022 344 2373

• <u>Github</u>

• LinkedIn

- Portfolio
- andrewjtrotter@gmail.com

Profile

Kia ora! I am a highly competent and patient software developer, with a talent for breaking down complex concepts and a passion for sharing knowledge. My journey through an intensive 15-week bootcamp has honed both my technical and soft skills, shaping me into a supportive and empathetic team player.

Mentoring comes natural to me as I always seek to support others. My knack for problem-solving is complemented by a professional and approachable demeanour. I also bring an eye for design, a continuous drive for learning and improvement, and a proclivity for leadership.

My ability to actively listen to people's needs and effectively provide solutions makes me a valuable addition to any team. As a firm believer in combining hard work with a sense of fun, I am excited to contribute to and learn from the industry.

Skills

Technical Skills

Human Skills

- ReactREST and
- Node.js GraphQL
- TypeScript Tailwind.css
- VitestExpress
- C# MySQL
- Mentoring
- Collaboration
- LeadershipAgile learner
- Communication
- Problem-Solving
- Empathy

Projects

Pinky Promise - Dev Academy Final

Live App | GitHub

A mobile-first web app to help keep yourself and friends accountable! A mobile-first app made for my final group project at Dev Academy. This was the first time I was exposed to an environment with user to user interaction. The challenge here was accommodating for users to have a relationship and see each other's promises regardless of who made it. I would like to improve the robustness around those interactions and style it more acceptably for desktop view.

Notable Tech: TypeScript, React, Tanstack, Vitest, Tailwind.css, Knex, Framer Motion

Website Template Editor by Da Dawgs

<u>GitHub</u>

As a learning group project, we made this to have a go at a basic website builder, focussing on allowing the user to change colours of elements in the sandbox. Partway through this project I discovered my planned implementation of the colour changing wouldn't work.



New Zealand Citizen

022 344 2373

• Github Portfolio

• andrewjtrotter@gmail.com

Projects continued

So, with 3 hours before the deadline, I researched and discovered a different approach.address sudden change and pivot during a stressful period.

Notable Tech: HTML, Express, Handlebars, SQLite3, Knex

Portfolio Website GitHub

I made this website after bootcamp to present myself and the projects I want to showcase. I took this opportunity to improve my front-end styling and adding cool little effects which I really enjoyed working on. I'm especially proud of the sticky panel and nav functionality.

Notable Tech: React, Tailwind.css TypeScript, Vite

Dungeons and Developers

GitHub

• LinkedIn

A group project with the goal of rolling some dice and getting some funny outcomes relevant to the developer experience. I was the Back End Lead, responsible for the access ,flow and shaping of data from the database to the front end. We also used ChatGPT to write our hilarious outcomes.

Notable Tech: React, Tailwind.css TypeScript, SQLite3, Knex, ChatGPT

Experience

Software Developer Student at Dev Academy

March - July 2023

- An indescribable 800 hours in 15 weeks of constant learning and growth to acquire the technical and human skills required for full stack web development in a modern framework. I learnt to learn incredibly fast with a focus on collaboration, self-awareness and giving/receiving feedback.
- We worked solo, in pairs and in teams to tackle a variety of challenges and create numerous <u>projects</u>. A focus on wellbeing, a growth mindset and empathy made this rigorous journey manageable and productive.
- As I had more experience in software engineering from my tertiary education, I used this opportunity to mentor and support my peers. This helped to foster the supportive environment and my peers were comfortable asking me for advice or to help unblock them.
- Leading the team with patience and generosity, I ensured that conflicts were swiftly resolved and productivity was maintained. This proactive approach was critical in delivering the app within the stringent sevenday deadline.



- New Zealand Citizen
- 022 344 2373
- <u>Github</u>
- andrewjtrotter@gmail.com
- Portfolio

• LinkedIn

Experience continued

Gallery Manager & Barista at Beautiful Things

Feb 2021 - Dec 2022

At Beautiful Things, I honed a diverse set of skills. As an exhibition coordinator, I sought out talented artists and liaised with them to digitise their artwork, boosting online visibility and sales. My role also included inventory management, order fulfilment, and ensuring our café maintained its reputation for serving great coffee.

Senior Digital Print Operator at Big Q Ltd

Mar 2017 - Dec 2021

As a Senior Digital Print Operator at Big Q Ltd, I effectively managed a dynamic production schedule, assuring top-quality products that met client expectations. I developed internal support systems, including production estimators to better assess resource estimation, and oversaw inventory management. My role also involved training and managing a

Education

Dev Academy Aotearoa

March - July 2023

New Zealand Certificate in Applied Software Development Tech: HTML, CSS, JS, TS, Handlebars, React, Redux, Tanstack, Vitest, Jest

Massey University

2021 - 2022

Bachelor of Information Sciences in Software Engineering Tech: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C++, C#, Dot NET

Interests

Volleyball

Bouldering

Playing Guitar

· Video Games

· Making Coffee

Technology

• Bush Walks

Learning

Referees are available upon request